# Kyle Liu

(323) 206-1038 | kyle116@yahoo.com | Los Angeles, CA kyle116.github.io github.com/kyle116 linkedin.com/in/liukyle

## **SUMMARY**

I am a web developer that works with programming languages such as HTML, CSS/Sass, JavaScript, and Ruby. I also make use of responsive design and SPA frameworks/libraries such as: React.js, Node.js, Express, Rails, jQuery, and Bootstrap. Before Web Development, I was a Valuation Analyst at a bank where I worked with large sets of data using SQL and Microsoft Excel, building models based on logic, inputs, and assumptions.

## **SKILLS**

Computer Languages:

JavaScript, HTML, CSS/Sass, Ruby, PHP

Databases:

PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Other Technologies:

AWS, JSON Web Token, Heroku

SPA Frameworks & Libraries:

Rails, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js

Version Control:

Git & Github

#### **PROJECTS**

Dodger 2 Player Game

- This game allows two people to play the game simultaneously, collecting points while dodging rocks.
- Technologies used: Javascript(with use of requestAnimationFrame), jQuery, HTML, and CSS

## Business Card Exchange

- A digital contacts app to keep track of all contacts you meet. This app is a full CRUD app and follows the MVC pattern. The app accesses PostgreSQL database and communicates with relational models.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails

## Bannd

- This app allows you to post stories about why you have been banned from an establishment.
- Technologies used: Node.js, Bootstrap, Express, AJAX requests, Yelp API and MongoDB

## Tender

- This app allows you to say yes and no to the pictures of food you like and matches you with the restaurant.
- Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, RESTful routes, Yelp API, Axios, and JWT

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

**General Assembly** - Teaching Assistant, August 2017 - Present CA

Santa Monica,

- Provide teaching and mentorship to 20 students in each Web Development class in programming in languages such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, Node.js, React.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Express, and Rails
- Lead TA sessions with help in class assignments, computer science topics, project building, and full stack development

# CIT Group - Valuation Analyst, April 2016 to May 2017

Pasadena, CA

- Created models and analyzed the bank's assets and portfolios utilizing large loan data sets (10,000+ rows)
- Construction and execution of complex financial models for valuation of portfolios using Excel, MS SQL Server, Hyperion, BlackRock, Citrix, and Bloomberg
- Quantitative and qualitative financial analysis, valuation of critical assets and liabilities, reconciling valuations to general ledger balances, preparing and reviewing quarterly bank's financials

## **EDUCATION**

California State Polytechnic Pomona - B.S. in Finance, September 2011 - December 2014

General Assembly, Santa Monica, CA - Web Development Immersive, May 2017 - August 2017